Guide to the Richard Kluger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Richard Kluger papers
1835-1995
MS 1443
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
31.67
(84 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, interview notes, and other materials which document Richard Kluger's professional career as a newspaper editor and author.
Kluger, Richard, 1934-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Richard Kluger, 1986-1987, 1996-1997.
Associated Materials
Related material: Brown vs. the Board of Education Papers (MS 759), Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Biographical / Historical
Richard Kluger was born in Paterson, New Jersey, on September 18, 1934. He graduated from Princeton (B.A.) in 1956. Kluger has written novels and articles, served in editorial capacities for the Wall Street Journal, the New York Post, Forbes magazine, the New York Herald Tribune, Book Week, and Simon and Schuster, and held the position of president and publisher of Charterhouse Books. He authored the Pulitzer Prize winning Ashes to Ashes, a history of the American tobacco industry.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, interview notes, and other materials which document Richard Kluger's professional career as a newspaper editor and author.
Conditions Governing Access
Folders 534 and 535 in box 45 of Accession 1997-M-023 may not be used without the permission of Richard Kluger.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series and one addition: I. Research and Interview Files. II. Subject Files. III. Topical Files
New York herald tribune; Cigarette industry -- United States -- History; Journalism; Newspapers -- New York (State); Smoking -- United States -- History; Tobacco industry -- United States -- History; Tobacco use -- United States -- History; Editors; Kluger, Richard, 1934-
- Research and Interview Files, Series I
  - Abramson, Jesse, 1953-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albert, Robert H., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alexander, Theresa [Hamilton], 1939-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen, George H., 1944-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alsop, Joseph
    - General, 1935-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Reporter's Trade, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Stay of Execution by Stewart Alsop, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ames, Helen, 1977, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Andrews, Bert
    - General, 1941-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hiss-Chambers case, 1962, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arm, Walter, 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Attwood, William, 1947, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baehr, Harry N., 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barnes, Joseph F.
    - General, 1928-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
    - General, 1972-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Oral history, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
  - Barnet, Sylvan J., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Barrett, Lawrence (Larry), 1962, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Beebe, Lucius, 1932, 1944, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Beech, Keyes, 1954, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Belford, Barbara, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Bellows, James G., 1948-1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Benchley, Robert and Nathaniel, 1932, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Berry, Warren, 1961, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bigart, Homer, 1940-1983 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
  - Bilby, Kenneth, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bird, Robert S., 1958-1968 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Blackman, M.C., 1965-1981 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bleeck, John, 1947-1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Blum, Danny, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Blum, John A., 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bogart, John, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Boyer, Philip, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Bradlee, Benjamin, 1971, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Braestrup, Peter, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Braynard, Frank, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Breslin, Jimmy, 1964-1984 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Broun, Heywood, 1917-1975 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Brundage, Howard, 1957-1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Bryan, Robert F., 1957-1983 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Buchwald, Art, 1928-1982 (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
  - Bugbee, Emma, 1912-1981 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Cameron, Barney G., 1954-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Canvin, Rue, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Carroll, Luke P., 1954-1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Carroll, Maurice (Mickey), undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Catledge, Turner, 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Clarity, James F., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Cook, Don, 1962-1982 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Cornish, George A., 1960-1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 56-57)
  - Cortissoz, Royal, 1941, 1945, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Crandell, Katherine K., 1983 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Crist, Judith, 1918-1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Cronkite, Walter, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Crosby, John, 1946-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Crow, C.P., 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Dana, Charles, 1861-1938, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Daniels, Judith, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Darling, Jay N., 1942, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Davis, Howard, 1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - deGramont, Sanche, 1960-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Denson, John, 1961-1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 69-71)
  - Diamond, Edwin, 1981-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Donovan, Robert J., 1941-1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 73-74)
  - Dougherty, Richard, 1981, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Draper, Gladys, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Drummond, Roscoe, 1949-1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Elliot, Osborn, 1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Engelking, Lessing L., 1933-1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Farris, Fred, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Fein, Nat, 1978-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Felker, Clay, 1962-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 82-84)
  - Ferretti, Fred, 1965-1983, undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Flexner, James Thomas, 1930, 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Forrest, Wilbur, 1927-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Forst, Donald H., 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Frankel, Max, 1983, undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Freeman, Ed, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Freidin, Seymour, 1945-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 91-92)
  - Fulbright, Newton, 1952-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Fuller, Margaret, 1845-1983, undated (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Gannett, Louis, 1929-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Gardner, Hy, 1949-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Garrett, Garet, 1954, 1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 97-98)
  - Genaver, Emily, 1949-1961, undated (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Gillies, Archibald, 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Glass, Andrew J., 1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Goldstein, Nathan, 1966-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Gottehrer, Barry, 1965-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Gould, Jay, 1884-1985 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Graham, Katherine, 1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Greeley, Horace, 1837-1855 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Greeley, Horace, 1956-1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 107-108)
  - Green, Monroe, 1935-1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Guernsey, Otis L., Jr., 1982, 1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Haddad, William, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Hadley, Arthur T., 1955-1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Hamilton, E. Douglas, 1957, 1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - Hammond, Percy, 1940, 1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Hamshar, Walter, 1981-1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Handler, Milton, 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Haxall, Bolling W., 1982-1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Hay, John (W.R. Thayer), 1871, 1908, undated (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Heckscher, August V., 1955-1981 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Heiskell, Marian, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Herzberg, Joseph, 1956-1974 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Higgins, Marguerite, 1950-1984 (Box 6, Folder 122-125)
  - Hill, Henley, undated (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Hills, Lee, 1949-1985 (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Holcomb, Allan, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Hopke, Dorothea, 1963-1982 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Hoving, Walter, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Huffman, Robert, 1966-1982 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Hupp, Charles M., 1984 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Hutchens, John K., undated (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Irwin, Don, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1983 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Kahn, E. J., 1981 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Kahn, Roger, undated (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Kallgren, Everett, 1969-1981 (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - Kandel, Myron, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Kanfer, Stefan, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Kaselow, Joseph, 1955-1965 (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - Keating, Michael F., 1982 (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Kehr, Ernie, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Kell, Ted, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - Kellett, Dee, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Kelley, Frank, 1940-1982 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Kerr, Walter, 1949-1983 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Kerr, Walter B., 1943-1985 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - Kihss, Peter, 1945-1983, undated (Box 7, Folder 149-150)
  - Kiker, Doug, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Kiley, Charles, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - King, Nicholas, 1941-1982 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Koyen, Ken, 1940-1985 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Krim, Seymour, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - Kupferberg, Herbert, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Lambert, Roft, 1962-1982 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Laney, Al, 1944-1981 (Box 7, Folder 158-159)
  - Laventhol, David, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Lawrence, David, 1937-1972 (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - Laymon, Theodore, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Levin, Carl, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Lewis, Bud, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - Lewis, Milton, 1947-1982 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Lindsay, Frank, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - Lindsay, John V., 1983 (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1931-1982 (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Lois, George, 1961-1982 (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Loory, Stuart, 1954-1982 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Lynn, James, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - MacDonald, Robert T., 1962-1981 (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - McAllister, James, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - McCrary, John, 1949-1984 (Box 8, Folder 174-175)
  - McGeehan, William, 1916-1982 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - McGurn, Barrett, 1956-1982 (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - Mann, May, 1956-1983 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Manning, Robert, 1958-1982 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Mapes, Lois, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Maxwell, Winslow, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Mearns, Jack, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Mergenthaler, Ottman, 1887-1954 (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Merrill, Francis Buss, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Messolonghitis, C.M., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Michalak, Joseph M., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - Midgley, Leslie, 1950-1982 (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Miller, William J., 1957-1985 (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Millis, Walter, 1940-1982 (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Mitchell, Joseph, 1935-1983 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - New York Tribune Inc. & Newspaper Guild of New York: Agreement, 1946-1965 (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Newborn, Roy H., 1962-1982 (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - Newman, Joseph, 1955-1981 (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - Noakes, Jane, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - O'Hara, Tom, 1940-1982 (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - O'Reilly, John, 1940-1982 (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Orton, William, 1878 (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Paddleford, Clementine, 1946-1984 (Box 8, Folder 198)
  - Palazzo, Peter, 1926-1983 (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - Paley, William, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Parsons, Geoffrey, Jr., 1946-1981 (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - Parsons, Geoffrey, Sr., 1952-1956 (Box 8, Folder 202)
  - Parsons, H. McIlvaine, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Parton, James, 1949-1985, undated (Box 9, Folder 204-205)
  - Parton, Margaret, 1947-1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Peck, Bob, 1955, 1972, undated (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - Persky, Mort, 1982, 1983, undated (Box 9, Folder 208)
  - Petersmeyer, C. Wrede, 1958-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - Peterson, Eve (Murphy), 1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Peyton, Bernhard, Jr., 1953, 1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Philbrick, Herbert A., 1949-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 212-213)
  - Pinkham, Richard, 1940-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - Portis, Charles, 1983, undated (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - Poteete, Robert, 1955-1984, undated (Box 9, Folder 216)
  - Powers, Bertram A., 1962-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 217-218)
  - Price, John: Round Robin correspondence, 1927-1976 (Box 9, Folder 219-221)
  - Price, John: Round Robin correspondence, 1976-1984, undated (Box 10, Folder 222-223)
  - Price, Raymond K., Jr., 1967, 1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - Racusin, M. Jay, 1961-1962, undated (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - Rees, Charles A., 1982, undated (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Reeves, Richard, 1965, 1982, undated (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Reid, Elizabeth Mills, 1910, 1913, 1931, undated (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - Reid, Helen Rogers, 1880-1977, undated (Box 10, Folder 229-236)
  - Reid, Joan Grynbaum, 1949, 1982, undated (Box 10, Folder 237)
  - Reid, Mary Louise, 1982, undated (Box 10, Folder 238)
  - Reid, Ogden "Brown", 1935-1955 (Box 10, Folder 239)
  - Reid, Ogden "Brown", 1956-1984, undated (Box 11, Folder 240-245)
  - Reid, Ogden, Sr., 1904-1954, undated (Box 11, Folder 246-248)
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1936-1985, undated (Box 11, Folder 249-251)
  - Reston, James B., 1956, undated (Box 11, Folder 252)
  - Rich, Alan, undated (Box 11, Folder 253)
  - Riis, Jacob, 1883-1985 (Box 11, Folder 254)
  - Ritchie, Kathryn, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 255)
  - Robinson, Thomas L., 1961-1983 (Box 11, Folder 256)
  - Robinson, William E., 1929-1950 (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - Robinson, William E., 1951-1983 (Box 12, Folder 258)
  - Rogers, Donald, 1954-1980 (Box 12, Folder 259)
  - Rogers, John, 1945, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 260)
  - Rogers, Warren, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 261)
  - Rooker, Thomas, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 262)
  - Root, Waverly, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 263)
  - Rosenfeld, Harry, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 264)
  - Rosenthal, Abe M., 1982 (Box 12, Folder 265)
  - Rosenthal, Harold, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 266)
  - Rosenthal, Jack, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 267)
  - Ross, Ishbel, 1926-1982 (Box 12, Folder 268)
  - Ryan, John F., 1981 (Box 12, Folder 269)
  - Safire, William, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 270)
  - Salisbury, Harrison E., 1982 (Box 12, Folder 271)
  - Sargent, Dwight, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 272)
  - Schaap, Dick, 1965-1982 (Box 12, Folder 273)
  - Schiff, Dorothy, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 274)
  - Schmidt, Benno C., 1983 (Box 12, Folder 275)
  - Schwarz, Ralph G., 1962-1982 (Box 12, Folder 276)
  - Schwed, Peter, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 277)
  - See, Arthur, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 278)
  - Sessa, Anthony, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 279)
  - Seymour, Gerald, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 280)
  - Shaplen, Robert, 1946, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 281)
  - Sheppard, Eugenia (and others), 1947-1984 (Box 12, Folder 282)
  - Sheppard, Ronald Z., 1981 (Box 12, Folder 283)
  - Shirer, William, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 284)
  - Silber, Fritz, 1941, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 285)
  - Simon, Maron J., 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 286)
  - Smalley, George, 1862-1911 (Box 12, Folder 287)
  - Smith, John Chabot, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 288)
  - Smith, Terence, 1965, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 289)
  - Smith, Walter (Red), 1946-1982 (Box 12, Folder 290)
  - Spinelli, Frank, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 291)
  - Stanford, Alfred, 1951-1982 (Box 12, Folder 292)
  - Steele, Richard C., 1960-1982 (Box 12, Folder 293)
  - Stone, Martin, 1966-1982 (Box 12, Folder 294)
  - Stowe, Leland, 1922-1983 (Box 12, Folder 295)
  - Straus, Jack, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - Streeter, Frank, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 297)
  - Sugrue, Francis, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 298)
  - Sugrue, Frank: "Who Killed the Tribune?", undated (Box 13, Folder 299)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 300)
  - Sulzberger, Iphigene, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 301)
  - Talbert, Ansel (Ed), 1940, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 302)
  - Talese, Gay, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 303)
  - Taylor, Bayard: "Travels", 1849-1853 (Box 13, Folder 304)
  - Taylor, Frank W., undated (Box 13, Folder 305)
  - Taylor, Telford, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 306)
  - Taylor, William E., 1964, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 307)
  - Terry, Walter, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 308)
  - Thallasinos, Gus, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 309)
  - Thayer, Walter, 1937-1985 (Box 13, Folder 310)
  - Thayer Files
    - General, 1957-1966 (Box 13, Folder 311-315)
    - Production department, 1964-1966 (Box 13, Folder 316)
    - Strike, 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 317)
  - Thees, Jack, 1954-1982 (Box 14, Folder 318)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1936-1973 (Box 14, Folder 319)
  - Thompson, Virgil, 1923-1983 (Box 14, Folder 320)
  - Thorn, Frank, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 321)
  - Tobin, Richard L., 1934-1982 (Box 14, Folder 322)
  - Torre, Marie
    - General (including Oliensis and Sheldon), 1955-1983 (Box 14, Folder 323)
    - "The Law and Freedom at the Press", 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 324)
  - Ubell, Earl, 1953-1982 (Box 14, Folder 325)
  - Van Doren, Irita (and Wilkie)
    - General, 1923-1982 (Box 14, Folder 326)
    - Publications, 1952-1982 (Box 15, Folder 327)
  - Van Horne, Richard, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 328)
  - Vartan, Vartanig, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 329)
  - Veit, Ivan, 1982-1985 (Box 15, Folder 330)
  - Wald, Richard C., 1960-1982 (Box 15, Folder 331)
  - Walker, Everett, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 332)
  - Walker, Stanley, 1928-1982 (Box 15, Folder 333)
  - Waring, T. R., 1982 (Box 15, Folder 334)
  - Warman, Morris, 1964-1984 (Box 15, Folder 335)
  - Waters, Frank T., 1982 (Box 15, Folder 336)
  - Weberman, Ben, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 337)
  - Webster, H.T., 1930-1954 (Box 15, Folder 338)
  - Weiss, Murray (Buddy), 1961-1982 (Box 15, Folder 339)
  - Wergeles, Ed, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 340)
  - West, Richard, 1961-1984 (Box 15, Folder 341)
  - Whitaker, John T., 1935-1982 (Box 15, Folder 342)
  - White, Robert M., II
    - General, 1982-1984 (Box 15, Folder 343)
    - Articles and accounts, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 344)
    - Documents of finances, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 345-347)
  - White, Stephen, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 348)
  - Whitman, Alden, 1981-1984 (Box 16, Folder 349)
  - Whitney, John Hay (Jock): Biographical and memorial, 1951-1985 (Box 16, Folder 350-351)
  - Whitney Files, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 352-355)
  - Whitney Files, 1960-1966 (Box 17, Folder 356-362)
  - Whitney Papers
    - General, 1957-1958 (Box 17, Folder 363-365)
    - Collection, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 366)
  - Whitney Speeches, 1961-1964 (Box 17, Folder 367)
  - Whitworth, William, 1964-1983 (Box 17, Folder 368)
  - Wilcox, Grafton, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 369)
  - Wilder, Roy, Jr., 1966-1985 (Box 17, Folder 370)
  - Winter, William, 1893-1917 (Box 17, Folder 371)
  - Wise, David, 1962-1983 (Box 17, Folder 372)
  - Wolfe, Tom
    - General, 1962-1983 (Box 17, Folder 373)
    - Articles and New Journalism, 1965-1983 (Box 18, Folder 374)
  - Woodward, Stanley, 1948-1979 (Box 18, Folder 375)
  - Wyden, Peter, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 376)
  - Yerxa, Fendall, 1974-1983 (Box 18, Folder 377)
  - Yoakum, Robert H., 1950-1982 (Box 18, Folder 378)
  - Young, John Russell, 1869 (Box 18, Folder 379)
  - Zalaznick, Sheldon, 1964-1981 (Box 18, Folder 380)
  - Zinsser, William K., 1958-1962 (Box 18, Folder 381)
  - Zwick, Lester, 1957-1985 (Box 18, Folder 382)
- Subject Files, Series II
  - Advertising and marketing
    - General, 1916-1966 (Box 19, Folder 383-384)
    - Fact Book II, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 385-386)
    - Gimbel v. Tribune, 1916-1917 (Box 19, Folder 387-388)
  - Annals
    - General, 1835-1883 (Box 19, Folder 389-400)
    - General, 1904-1957 (Box 20, Folder 401-423)
    - General, 1958-1964, undated (Box 21, Folder 424-432)
    - Articles, 1961-1963 (Box 22, Folder 433-434)
    - Borden, Lizzie, 1893 (Box 22, Folder 435)
  - Circulation and advertising, 1877-1981 (Box 22, Folder 436-437)
  - Financial
    - General, 1903-1965 (Box 22, Folder 438-439)
    - Committees, 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 440)
    - Corporate minute books, 1849-1966 (Box 22, Folder 441-442)
  - General
    - Ayer Cup, 1918-1982 (Box 22, Folder 443)
    - "Book Week", 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 444)
    - Brooklyn Eagle, 1953-1982 (Box 22, Folder 445)
    - Forums, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 446)
    - Fresh Air Fund, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 447)
    - Guild, 1936-1983 (Box 23, Folder 448)
    - Herald history, 1862-1981 (Box 23, Folder 449)
    - Kluger, Richard, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 450)
    - "New York City in Crisis", 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 451)
    - Paris edition, 1938-1984 (Box 23, Folder 452-453)
    - Pulitzer Prizes, 1974-1981 (Box 23, Folder 454)
    - Sunday edition, 1957-1964 (Box 23, Folder 455)
    - Technology and equipment, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 456)
    - Tribune history, 1937-1966 (Box 23, Folder 457)
    - Ubel and the Media, 1981-1983 (Box 23, Folder 458)
    - Washington Bureau, 1958-1981 (Box 23, Folder 459)
    - Washington Star, 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 460)
    - World Journal Tribune, 1966-1968 (Box 24, Folder 461)
  - Labor Relations
    - Bogart
      - General, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 462)
      - Annual reports, 1954-1966 (Box 24, Folder 463)
      - Monthly reports, 1958-1967 (Box 24, Folder 464-465)
    - Boycotter, 1884-1894 (Box 24, Folder 466)
  - Legal/Libel/Confidentiality
    - Burdick v. U.S., 1914-1948 (Box 24, Folder 467)
    - Personalities, undated (Box 24, Folder 468)
  - Subject worksheets
    - Advertising - World Herald Tribune (Box 24, Folder 469)
    - Books and long articles (Box 24, Folder 470-472)
- Topical Files, Series III
  - Articles, 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 473-475)
  - Audio tape
    - Cook, Don, undated (Box 25, Folder 476)
    - Engelking, L.L., undated (Box 25, Folder 477)
  - Correspondence 1965 - 1967 Apr (Box 25, Folder 478-481)
  - Correspondence 1967 May-1970 (Box 26, Folder 482-495)
  - Correspondence 1971 - 1977 May (Box 27, Folder 496-514)
  - Correspondence 1977 Jun - Dec (Box 28, Folder 515)
  - Correspondence A - W, 1962-1966 (Box 28, Folder 516-534)
  - Demise of the New York Herald Tribune
    - Articles, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 535)
    - Letters, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 536)
  - Printed material, 1934-1967, undated (Box 29, Folder 537-540)
  - Writing
    - "The New York Herald Tribune Since the Civil War," by Harry W. Baehr, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 541-544)
    - "Rewrite Man", undated (Box 30, Folder 545-548)
  - Photographs used in The Paper: Life and Death of the New York Herald Tribune, 1920s-1963 (Box 31, Folder 549-555)
    Scope and Contents
    Received from: Richard Kluger, 1987.
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-023
  General
  Folders 17-19 were removed at the request of the donor.
  This addition to the Richard Kluger Papers consists of research materials compiled for the preparation of Ashes to Ashes: America's Hundred Year Cigarette War, the Public Health, and the Unabashed Triumph of Philip Morris, 1996. As much as possible, Kluger's folder headings and arrangements have been retained.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Folders 534 and 535 in box 45 may not be used without permission of Richard Kluger.
  - Company files [contents vary from folder to folder, but may include correspondence, printed materials, working papers, biographical information, and Kluger interview materials]
    - American Brands, Inc., 1969-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Tobacco Company (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - General, 1925-1968, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
      - Hahn, Paul M., 1950, 1958, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Heimann, Robert K., 1948-1986, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Walker, Robert B., 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Weaver, Sylvester (Pat), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Brown and Williamson, 1951-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Liggett and Myers
      - General, 1951-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)